hey guys welcome back
and today we are going to talk about
buffer operations what are the different
operations which are available uh in the
t-box automation module and how you can
use them in your test cases now this
will be a continuation uh from our
previous session when we talked about
different string operations and then we
used it to actually resolve one of
automation challenge right so we used it
to basically extract this particular
order number from this text okay and we
use different string operations we also
used the t-box buffer Right Said buffer
and we also used the action mode buffer
right so we have seen some of the
operations which we are already using
but I'm going to talk explicitly about
all of these operations okay
so we have already seen how you can
resolve this problem of getting the
order number using this complex
expression which involves a lot of
different string operations right so we
used the trim operation we use the
string replace to replace that
particular text with some um
space or white space and then we also
used the ignore case inside that in
order to get that particular order
number so that works perfectly fine it's
um it's a valid way of getting this
order number but there is also another
way to do this okay and I'm going to
show you exactly that
so
um I have created a test case folder and
I'm going to reuse this test case so I'm
going to copy and paste it here okay
and inside this I'm going to now uh
delete this particular test step because
I don't want to use this string
operations okay I may use some of them
but not all of them I want to show you
another way of doing that okay so this
particular step where we are getting the
inner text and we are buffering that
into this particular value B underscore
order so that will still remain the same
okay we want to get the text which is
present in this particular page and we
want to buffer it using the action mode
so that that's fine now I'm going to
show you all the different buffer
operations which are available in Tosca
okay so when you go into this ADD test
step and you type t-box and buffer
so these are all the four different
operations which you can perform okay so
we have already seen t-box set buffer it
basically uh sets a buffer value right
and then there is also name to buffer
we'll see this that is delete buffer
which will basically delete the buffer
okay and then there is t-box partial
buffer okay so if you want to basically
extract a part of the value and buffer
it then you can use the partial buffer
okay
so this name to buffer this will
basically what it will do is it will
allow you to buffer the name of the test
case okay that uses that particular
module okay so it's not a a very kind of
common scenario you will do always but
it could be useful in in some steps okay
so we will see this how how to use this
but do keep in mind that this name to
buffer can will only work when you run
it from execution list it will not work
when you run it from scratchbook as it
doesn't support this particular
functionality okay
so let's go ahead and use all of these
modules now okay so I'm going to start
with t-box set buffer okay so once we
get this in our text
um inside this buffer uh what we want to
do
we want to extract the order number okay
so let's see how we can do this
um I'm going to call it order num and
here
actually I could get the order number
but what we need to do is we need to
First trim this white spaces okay there
is no other way of doing this we have to
trim the white spaces okay because
otherwise you will always get the white
space even if I try to extract the
partial buffer value okay
so first we need to do this and for this
again we'll be using the trim function
like we have done before okay inside
this I'm going to pass the buffer value
which is B underscore order
okay
and this will basically trim all the
white spaces inside this text which we
are getting okay
so this uh will set the buffer okay so
this particular buffer operation is used
to
set the buffer so it will create a
buffer with a particular value the value
is this what we are trimming okay and
then um it will
um set it into a buffer name which is
order num okay so this is what the set
buffer does already we have used this
many times but I'm just explaining you
again okay it can also verify the value
okay if I change the action mode to
verify then it is going to verify the
value for this particular buffer so this
t-box set buffer can be used for both it
can be used for creating a buffer with a
particular value it can also be used for
verifying the value of existing buffer
okay
um now what we are going to do is we are
going to now use another module called T
box
uh
partial buffer okay
so this is where we are going to extract
a part of the value okay so part of the
text and store it into a buffer right
so here we need to pass couple of values
okay
so we need to pass uh what would be the
buffer new buffer name okay where you
want to store this so say I'm going to
store it in order number and then in the
value you need to pass the actual buffer
okay so from where you want to extract
this partial text and that is uh order
number right so we'll use buffer here
and we will use order num
okay
and then uh we what we need to give here
is either we can give it a start okay a
start value this is basically the index
from which you want the system to start
buffering or verifying the value okay
and then you can also put a end value
okay so uh see for example here uh we
want to extract this particular text
okay so either you give it a start value
okay so it could be after all of these
characters right so you need to count
all of this and then it could be 20 30
uh so whatever is the start value and
then the end value okay
but this is not the ideal scenario for
this purpose okay uh start and end could
be useful when you are starting right in
the beginning right so if I want to
extract this order text I can give it
um a start value like 1 here okay
and then um I can give it uh one two
three four five right so I can give it a
end value of five so it will basically
extract the first five characters right
starting from one till five whatever
characters it will get it will extract
that and it will store it in this
particular order num right
but that is not what I want to do I want
to extract the order number and the best
way to do is is to use
um this particular parameter which is
last okay
so this will basically uh you have to
give the number of characters you want
to buffer or verify starting from the
last character okay so you need to
decide which parameters you want to use
in this partial buffer which suits your
particular use case Okay so for my use
case uh it this last parameter suits
better okay so if I count from the last
one two three four five six seven right
so seven characters I want to extract
okay
so you cannot do a combination of both
okay because it will contract each other
right so better I will just delete this
and then here I will give last seven
okay so it will buffer the last seven
characters from this particular text
okay and into this buffer value
right I can also use the same t-box
partial buffer to verify okay same for
t-box set buffer you can do that but
let's use the partial buffer here again
and here I need to pass the same buffer
value which is order number
and then in the value I need to pass
this particular order number
obviously this is not an ideal case for
this but I just want to verify it
ideally I would not know this order
number because it's dynamically
generated but in any other use case
where you already know the value it is
coming from the requirements you can use
the partial buffer to even verify this
okay so you just need to change the
action mode to verify
right and now uh we'll be using another
module okay which is t-box set
um or let's type buffer here
and name to buffer okay
so here uh
we have to give basically a name okay a
value where this particular name will be
stored it will store the test case name
okay so we'll say test case underscore
name here
and this will basically allow you to
buffer the name of the test case okay
which uses this particular module right
and it will only work with execution
list it will not work with when you run
it from scratchbook right
and the last uh t-box
buffer operation which I want to show
you is delete buffer okay
this could be useful if you want to
clean up whatever buffer names you have
used okay
uh it's not necessary because whenever
you run it will always override the
values but still if you want to do a
cleanup you can always do that right
so let's see what buffer names we have
already used I can delete all of them at
the time okay so I have used order num
somewhere right here and then I have
also used order number
and then
I have also used TC underscore name
okay so these are the three buffers
which I have used you can see here
okay and at the last step I am basically
deleting all these three buffers right
so you can see here I have used all the
different buffer operations okay for
this particular scenario
um we are using the set buffer we are
using partial buffer to basically
store the partial
buffer paths okay and also verify it
using the same method okay and then name
to buffer we'll see what it gives and
also the buffer to delete all the buffer
names right
so let's go ahead and run this
particular test case now and let me show
you the result okay as I said it's
better to run it from execution list if
you want to see the result for name to
buffer
so let me create execution list I
already have a folder here okay and I am
going to drag this particular test case
here
okay
and I'm going to say
um order number
find order number
okay and then this will contain my test
case so let's go ahead and execute it
right from here
okay so the execution has passed and
let's look at the results now okay so
here if I come here
you will see here
um in the log info we can see
P underscore order has been set to the
value this right it has got some white
space characters
and then if we come here and here we are
trimming the value or white spaces from
the text right so there are no white
spaces in this
now we want to extract the order number
right so here
now I'm buffering that a particular
part of the text right so the last part
so it counts from the last till the
character or what the value I have
provided I provide seven so it counted
and it grabbed this particular text
which is actually the order number so I
have set it to this particular buffer
right
and again here I'm verifying okay
whether these two are equal so these two
are actually same so it has passed and
then we are using the Box name to buffer
here we are storing the test case name
so you can see this is the test case
name find order number it has been
stored in this particular buffer name
which is TC underscore name okay
and then uh t-box Delete buffer so here
you will see buffer what a number was
successfully deleted so it deleted all
the three buffers which we had created
earlier so performed a cleanup okay
so these are all the different
operations which you can perform using
the t-box automation modules for buffers
right
um it could be useful in different
scenarios so you have to look at your
use case and then use any of this uh
buffer operations inside your test case
so that's all for this particular video
hopefully you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today I will continue to
bring more interesting videos on Tosca
on different features of Tosca and how
you can use it in your day-to-day
automation scenarios so keep watching
and until the next video keep learning
Tosca and keep watching our channel for
more upcoming videos